Finding Aid for Law School (University of Michigan), 1852-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The Law School Records begin in 1852 and span the years through the end of the twentieth century. The records document the history of legal education at the University of Michigan, the administration of the Law School, and the lives of some of the scholars who have studied and taught there.
The physical arrangement of the records reflects the various accessions of material that have been received from the Law School over the years. This finding aid is structured to reflect the intellectual organization of the records - continuing series and like materials have been brought together regardless of when the records were transferred to the library. The Summary Contents List provides and overview of the organization of the records.
There are eight major series in the record group: Historical and Class Files (1865-1974); Deans of the Law School (1852-1999); Faculty Files (1859-1994); Student Files (1894-1996); Law Quadrangle and William W. Cook, (1919-1938); Law School Lecture Series; Committee of Visitors and Audio/Visual Materials.
Summary Contents List
Historical and Class Files [Box 1] Class Files, 1866-1914 [Box 1] Historical Files, 1865-1994
Deans of the Law School [Boxes 2-59; 69-75 and 81-112] Deans' Files, 1852-1975 [Box 2-44] Harry B. Hutchins, 1904-1910 [Box 2] Henry M. Bates, 1910-1939 [Boxes 2-32] E. Blythe Stason, 1939-1960 [Boxes 26-39] Allan F. Smith, 1960-1964 [Boxes 39-41] Allan F. Smith and Charles W. Joiner, 1961-1966 [Boxes 42-44] Francis A. Allen, 1966-1971 [Boxes 44-48 and 81] Theodore J. St. Antoine, 1971-1978 [Boxes 69-72 and 82-85] Terrence Sandalow, 1980-1994 [Boxes 85-86] Lee C. Bollinger, 1987-1994 [Boxes 86-90] Topical Files, 1896-1997 [Boxes 48-58 and 101-112] Regents Communications, Reports and Petitions, 1852-1962 [Box 59] Deanship Search Committee, 1986-1987 and 1993 -1994 [Boxes 73 and 75, restricted] Course Evaluations, 1971-1979 [Box 74] Administrators, 1954-1986 [Boxes 91-92] Committees, 1951-1995 [Boxes 50-52 and 93-96] Programs and Projects, 1960-1997 [Boxes 96-101]
Faculty Files [Boxes 59-63 and 112-115] Memos to the Faculty, 1966-1994 [Box 112] Minutes, 1859-1870, 1894-1960 [Boxes 59-62] Personnel Files, 1939-1999 [Boxes 112-114; Boxes 119-121, restricted] Publications, Research and Activities, 1963-1994 [Box 115] Record of Lectures, 1870-1897 [Box 63] Salaries, 1965-1993 [Box 115]
Student Files [Boxes 63-64 and 116-117] Courses 1897-1901 [Box 63] Case Club/Practice Court Records, 1894-1971 [Box 63] Student Organizations, 1898-1985 Student Organizations [1999 Accession], 1962-1996 [Boxes 116-117]
William W. Cook Lectures [Box 76] Lectureship Committee, 1941-1975 [Box 76] Lecturer Files, 1965-1993 [Box 76]
Thomas M. Cooley Lectures [Box 77] General Correspondence, 1961-1975 [Box 77] Lecturer Files, 1969-1993 [Box 77]
Committee of Visitors [Boxes 78-80] Meeting Files, 1963-1993 [Boxes 78-80]
Audio/Visual Materials [Boxes 68 and 117-118] Photographs [Boxes 68 and 117 and outsize folder] Audiocassettes, 1987-1995 [Box 118] Videocassettes, 1989-1995 [Box 118]
Subjects:
Hutchins Hall (University of Michigan); Lawyers' Club (University of Michigan); University of Michigan--Administration.Administration.; University of Michigan--Buildings.Buildings.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; University of Michigan--Law School.Law School.; Law.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Acheson, Dean, 1893-1971.; Dominick's (Restaurant: Ann Arbor, Mich.); Law Quadrangle (University of Michigan); United States. Judge Advocate General's School (Ann Arbor, Mich.); University of Michigan--Buildings.Buildings.; University of Michigan--Faculty.Faculty.; University of Michigan. Law Library.; University of Michigan--Law School.Law School.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs.StudentsSocial life and customs.; University of Michigan--Students.Students.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Restaurants.; African Americans.; Restaurants--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Television in education.; World War, 1939-1945--Education and the war.; World War, 1939-1945--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Construction industry.; Courtrooms.; Military parades and ceremonies.; Soldiers--American--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Televisions.
Cartoons.; Drawings.; Photographs.
Contributors:
Allen, Frances Alfred, 1919-; Bates, Henry Moore, 1869-1949.; Bollinger, Lee C., 1946-; Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.; Joiner, Charles Wycliffe, 1916-; Sandalow, Terrance, 1934-; Smith, Allan Frederick, 1911-; Stason, E. Blythe (Edwin Blythe), 1891-1972.; St. Antoine, Theodore J., 1929-
- Historical and Class Files, 1865-1974
  The Historical and Class Files [Pre-1985 Accessions] (1865-1974, 0.75 linear feet) consist largely of assorted manuscripts and newspaper articles relating primarily to Law School classes graduating between 1866 and 1914. These files, which are not comprehensive, include material on class reunions and fragmentary information on former students. Of note is a student autograph book in the "Class of 1879" folder. Historical material includes miscellaneous correspondence, 1865-1974, which contains a student letter from 1865 and several examples of student withdrawal letters from the 1880s. For further information on various classes researchers should search the University of Michigan on-line catalog (MIRLYN) under University of Michigan--Law School--Class of [specific class] for printed reports, directories, and class notes for individual classes.
  - Class of, 1866-1911 (Box 1)
    (folder for each class year except for 1867-1871, 1878, 1883-1884, 1886, 1902)
  - Class of 1929 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Historical and Miscellaneous), 1865-1974 (Box 1)
  - "Human Interest", 1948-1957 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1946-1960 (Box 1)
- Deans of the Law School, 1852-1999
  The Deans of the Law School series represents the central administrative files of the Dean's office and several top administrators. The series is divided into nine subseries:, Deans' Files, 1852-1975; Francis Allen; Theodore St. Antoine; Terrence Sandalow; Lee Bollinger; Administrators; Committees; Programs and Projects; and Topical Files. The files include correspondence, topical files, reports, and memos to the faculty.
  - Deans' Files, 1852-1975
    Records in the Deans' Files, 1852 to 1975, consist primarily of correspondence and topical files of Law School deans after 1900. This subseries includes all Law School records accessioned prior to 1985. The subseries contains three separate files: Correspondence Files; Topical Files; and Regents Communications, Reports, and Petitions.
    - Correspondence Files, 1904-1971
      The Correspondence Files (46.5 linear feet, 1904-1971) consist largely of correspondence maintained by deans Harry B. Hutchins, Henry M. Bates, E. Blythe Stason, Allan F. Smith, Charles Joiner (acting dean), and Francis Allen. The files covering the period 1904-1913 have been retained in the chronological order in which they were maintained. The files after 1913 were kept in their original order, alphabetically by year or range of years. The alphabetically arranged files typically contain a general folder for each letter and occasionally an individual folder for a significant topic. Unfortunately, there is no subject access or index to these files. Researchers should note that there is a fair amount of overlap between the between the files. The correspondence files continue in the subseries of individual deans.
      - 1904-1913
        - 1904-March 1911 (Box 2)
        - April 1911-March 1912 (Box 3)
        - April 1912-November 1912 (Box 4)
        - December 1912-September 1913 (Box 5)
      - 1913-1914
        - A-Z (Box 6)
      - 1914-1915
        - A-Z (Box 7)
      - 1915-1916
        - A-Z (Box 8)
      - 1917-1918
        - A-J (Box 9)
        - K-Z (Box 10)
      - 1918-1926
        - A-Bm (Box 11)
        - Bo-Com (Box 12)
        - Com-G (Box 13)
        - H-Li (Box 14)
        - Li-O (Box 15)
        - P-Sm (Box 16)
        - Sm-Z (Box 17)
      - 1927-1932
        - A-Cn (Box 18)
        - Co-G (Box 19)
        - H-Mh (Box 20)
        - Mi-Sh (Box 21)
        - Si-Z (Box 22)
      - 1933-1934
        - A-E (Box 23)
        - F-Q (Box 24)
        - R-Z (Box 25)
      - 1934-1946
        - A (Box 26)
        - B-C (Box 27)
        - C-F (Box 28)
        - G-L (Box 29)
        - L-N (Box 30)
        - O-S (Box 31)
        - S-Z (Box 32)
      - 1947-1954
        - A-C (Box 33)
        - C-H (Box 34)
        - H-L (Box 35)
        - L-R (Box 36)
        - S-Z (Box 37)
      - 1955-1960
        - A-L (Box 38)
          - Centennial Committee of the Law School (Box 38)
          - Committees, Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 38)
          - Cook, William W (Box 38)
        - M-Z (Box 39)
          - State Bar of Michigan (Box 39)
          - Summer Sessions (Box 39)
          - Supreme Court Clerkships (Box 39)
      - 1960-1964
        - A-C
          - Association of American Law Schools, 3 folders (Box 39)
          - Atomic Energy Studies (Box 39)
        - C-O (Box 40)
          - Committees, Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 40)
          - Cook, W. W (Box 40)
          - Faculty Activities, 2 folders (Box 40)
          - Ford Foundation, 2 folders (Box 40)
          - Hatcher, Harlan (Box 40)
          - Hawkland, William D (Box 40)
          - Heyns, Roger W (Box 40)
          - Lawyers Club, 3 folders (Box 40)
        - P-Z (Box 41)
      - 1963-1964
        - A-Z
          - George, B. J. Jr (Box 41)
          - Harris, Robert J (Box 41)
          - Harvey, W. B (Box 41)
          - Kimball, Spencer L (Box 41)
          - Stein, Eric (Box 41)
      - 1961-1966
        - A-F (Box 42)
          - Association of American Law Schools (Box 42)
          - Case Club (Box 42)
          - Chinese Communist Law Project (Box 42)
          - Chuo University (Box 42)
          - Citizens Committee for Higher Education (Box 42)
          - Civil Rights Research Council (Box 42)
          - Cook, W. W., Lectureship Committee (Box 42)
          - Ford Foundation
            - Criminal Justice (Box 42)
            - International Legal Studies (Box 42)
            - New Ford Grant (Box 42)
            - Miscellaneous (Box 42)
        - G-S (Box 43)
          - Institute of Continuing Legal Education (Box 43)
          - Institute for Foreign and Comparative Law (Box 43)
          - Institute of International Education (Box 43)
          - Law School Fund (Box 43)
          - Supreme Court Clerkships (Box 43)
        - T-Z (Box 44)
          - Television (Box 44)
          - Visitors (Box 44)
      - 1966-1968
        - A-K (Box 44)
        - L-Z (Box 45)
      - 1968-1971
        - A-J (Box 46)
        - K-S (Box 47)
        - T-Z (Box 48)
    - Topical Files, 1896-1975
      The alphabetically arranged Topical Files (10.5 linear feet, 1896-1975), contain records of administration, organizations, faculty activities and functions, and national and state associations. Although the records in this file date from as early as 1896, the bulk of the material is from the 1950s and 1960s. The development of various committees within the Law School, e.g. the curriculum committee, is well documented in this series as is the Lawyers Club and the role of the School during World Wars I and II. World War I documentation includes two folders relating to the military records of law students as well as material on the Students' Army Training Corps. The World War II era is particularly well documented, including the activities of the Judge Advocate General's (JAG) School which relocated from Washington, D.C. to the Law School during the war. Also noteworthy are the folders on the Association of American Law Schools (1912-1914) which include correspondence with William H. Taft and Felix Frankfurter. Additional topical files, with overlapping dates and coverage, have arrived in subsequent accessions. As such, researchers may find it advisable to consult the Topical Files maintained in the records of individual deans and the separate Topical Files subseries.
      - Academic Affairs Advisory Council, 1963-1966; 2 folders (Box 48)
      - Admissions Office, 1947-1969 (Box 48)
      - Alumni, 1961-1969 (Box 48)
      - Alumni Society, Undated (Box 48)
      - Alumni Surveys, 1966-1969 (Box 48)
      - American Bar Association, 1919-1972; 5 folders (Box 48)
      - American Institute of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1912; 2 folders (Box 48)
      - American Journal of Comparative Law (Box 48)
      - American Law Institute, 1932-1941 (Box 48)
      - Association of American Law Schools
        - Correspondence, 1912-1914; 8 folders (Box 49)
        - Teachers Directory, 1964-1970 (Box 49)
        - Miscellaneous, 1970-1972 (Box 49)
      - Atomic Energy Legal Research Program, 1958-1962 (Box 49)
      - Barristers Society, 1956-1963 (Box 49)
      - Benedum, Claude Worthington, Foundation, 1964-1968 (Box 49)
      - Bexelius, Hon. Alfred, 1968 (Box 49)
      - Broomfield Essay Competition, 1961-1967 (Box 49)
      - Budgets
        - Notes and Correspondence
          - 1926-1948, 3 folders (Box 49)
          - 1966-1978, 2 folders (Box 49)
        - William W. Cook Endowment and Research Fund
          - Minutes, 1939/40-1946/47 (Box 49)
          - Minutes, 1949/50-1954/55 (Box 49)
          - Reports and Miscellaneous, 1956-1975 (Box 49)
      - Buhl Bequest, 1896-1897 (Box 49)
      - Butzel, Henry M., 1963-1965 (Box 49)
      - Class Scheduling, 1966/67-1967/68 (Box 49)
      - Classroom Utilization Study, 1956-1957 (Box 49)
      - COIF Award, 1969-1971 (Box 49)
      - Clinical Programs, 1968 (Box 49)
      - Closed Circuit Television Programs, 1962 (Box 49)
      - Colombian Proposal, 1968-1969 (Box 49)
      - Combined Curriculum, Students Enrolled in Law/LS&A, 1896/97-1955/56; 3 folders (Box 49)
      - Committees
        - Committee on Size of the Law School, 1962-1965 (Box 50)
        - Committee on Year Round Operation, 1961-1962 (Box 50)
        - Committee to Educate Lawyers for Trial Experience, 1965 (Box 50)
        - Curriculum Committee
          - File Index, 1934-1963/64 (Box 50)
          - 1934-1937/38 (Box 50)
          - 1939/40-1941/42 (Box 50)
          - 1945/1946-1953/1954, 11 folders (Box 50)
          - 1954/55-1963/64, 14 folders (Box 51)
        - Standing Committee, 1956-1966
          - Ad Hoc Committee on Honorary Degrees (Box 52)
          - Ad Hoc Committee to Consider Law Faculty Representation on Senate Assembly (Box 52)
          - Administrative Committee (Box 52)
          - Curriculum Committee (Box 52)
          - Faculty Committee Appointments (Box 52)
          - Graduate and Research Committee, 4 folders (Box 52)
          - Law Review Advisory Committee (Box 52)
          - Library Advisory Committee (Box 52)
          - Scholarship Awards Committee (Box 52)
          - Student-Faculty Committee (Box 52)
          - Student Loan Committee (Box 52)
        - Standing Committee, 1966/67
          - Administrative Committee (Box 52)
          - Admission Policy Committee (Box 52)
          - Curriculum Committee (Box 52)
          - Graduate and Research Committee (Box 52)
          - Law Review Advisory Committee (Box 52)
        - Standing Committee, 1967/68
          - Administrative Committee (Box 52)
          - Admissions Policy Committee (Box 52)
          - Building Committee (Box 52)
          - Curriculum Committee (Box 52)
          - Graduate and Research Committee (Box 52)
          - Miscellaneous Committees (Box 52)
        - Standing Committee, 1968/69
          - Administrative Committee (Box 52)
          - Admissions Policy Committee (Box 52)
          - Building Committee (Box 52)
          - Curriculum Committee (Box 52)
          - Miscellaneous Committees (Box 52)
      - Concordance of Latin American Commercial Law, 1967-1969 (Box 53)
      - Conference on Deans, 1961-1965 (Box 53)
      - Curriculum Studies, 1960-1965; 2 folders (Box 53)
      - Deans' Conferences Minutes, 1920-1932 (Box 53)
      - Dean Selection Committee, 1965 (Box 53)
      - Deanship Search Committee, 1970/71 (Box 53)
      - Degree Requirements, 1950-1951 (Box 53)
      - Distinguished Alumni Sesquicentennial Award Law, 1967 (Box 53)
      - Durfee, Edgar Noble, 1958 (Box 53)
      - Dzendzel Proposal, 1966 (Box 53)
      - Ethics Lectures, 1961-1965 (Box 53)
      - Executive Committee of the Summer Session, 1960-1962 (Box 53)
      - Faculty
        - Activities, 1963-1966 (Box 53)
        - Memoranda
          - Discussion of Law School Expansion, 1965 (Box 53)
          - Goals for the Law School, 1960-1970 (Box 53)
          - News of the Faculty, 1964-1966; 2 folders (Box 53)
        - Research, 1964/65 (Box 53)
      - Federal Bureau of Prisons, 1969-1971
        - Financial Statements (Box 53)
        - Meetings and Seminars (Box 53)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 53)
      - Films, 1961-1965 (Box 53)
      - Fire Report, 1961 (Box 53)
      - Ford Foundation
        - Foreign Graduate Study and Research (Box 54)
          - Original Papers, 1954-1961; 3 folders (Box 54)
          - Proposals, 1965; 2 folders (Box 54)
          - Reports, 1953/54-1968/69; 2 folders (Box 54)
            (see also Box 107)
        - Grant-Atomic Legal Research, 1958-1962 (Box 54)
        - International Studies Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 54)
      - Grade Norms Committee, 1960-1962 (Box 54)
      - Grading Regulations, 1934-1949 (Box 54)
      - Graduate Office, 1961-1966 (Box 54)
      - Honorary Degrees, 1958-1959 (Box 54)
      - Honors and Honors Banquet, 1951-1960; 1962-1970; 4 folders (Box 54)
      - Hutchins Hall and Legal Research Building
        [see also oversized material]
        - Floor Plans (Box 54)
        - Windows and Portraits (Box 54)
      - Institute of Continuing Education (Box 54)
      - Institutionalization of Mentally Abnormal Persons, 1964-1967 (Box 54)
      - Inter-American Bar Association, 1948-1949 (Box 54)
      - Jerome (Thomas Spencer) Fund, 1922 (Box 54)
      - Judicial Administration-Research and Instruction, 1968 (Box 54)
      - Judicial Law Clerks, 1963-1966 (Box 54)
      - Juris Doctor Degree, 1967-1968 (Box 54)
      - Law Buildings, 1923-1934; 2 folders
        - Clippings on Law Quadrangle, 1924-1934 (Box 54)
        - Property Costs for Law School and Lawyers Club Site, 1923 (Box 54)
      - Law Dean's Lament (Poem) (Box 54)
      - Law Library
        - 1963-1964 (Box 55)
        - 1965-1966 (Box 55)
        - 1967-1970 (Box 55)
      - Law Library Memos, 1966-1970 (Box 55)
      - Law Library Reports
        - 1955-1960 (Box 55)
        - 1961-1963 (Box 55)
      - Law School Alumni Scholarship Fund, 1955-1962 (Box 55)
      - Law School Centennial Fund, 1960 (Box 55)
      - Law School Fund
        - Correspondence
          - 1966-1968 (Box 55)
          - 1968-1971, 3 folders (Box 55)
          - 1971-1973, 3 folders (Box 55)
        - Memorials, 1967-1972; 2 folders (Box 55)
        - National Committee Meetings
          - 1967 (Box 55)
          - 1968 (Box 55)
      - Lawyers Club
        - Administrative Records, 1959-1971
          - 1959-1964 (Box 55)
          - 1965-1966, 2 folders (Box 55)
          - 1967-1968, 2 folders (Box 56)
          - 1968-1969, 3 folders (Box 56)
          - 1969-1971, 3 folders (Box 56)
        - Special Alumni Committee, 1968 (Box 56)
      - Legal Aid Clinic, 1965 (Box 56)
      - Legal Education Seminar, 1968 (Box 56)
      - Legal Writing-Problems and Research, 1957-1964 (Box 56)
      - Michigan Law Review, 1951-1970 (Box 56)
      - Michigan Legal Publications, 1955-1966 (Box 56)
      - Military Service Meeting, 1968 (Box 56)
      - Mozolin, Professor V.P., 1966 (Box 56)
      - Office Relocation, 1966-1968 (Box 56)
      - Ohta, Tomoyaki, 1966 (Box 56)
      - Pfenningstorf, Dr. Werner, 1966 (Box 56)
      - Placement of Michigan Men in Washington, D.C., 1964-1965 (Box 56)
      - Placement Records, 1955/56-1962/63 (Box 56)
      - Pre-Law Students Reading List, 1944-1961 (Box 56)
      - Preliminary Week Instructions, 1956-1966 (Box 56)
      - Procedure Courses, 1963 (Box 56)
      - Professional Responsibility, 1961 (Box 56)
      - Prospectus: A Journal of Law Reform, 1966-1968; 3 folders (Box 56)
      - Publications of Law Faculty and Research Staff, 1948-1961 (Box 57)
      - Required Curriculum Committee, 1963 (Box 57)
      - Research in Inter-American Law, 1966 (Box 57)
      - Russell Sage Foundation, 1959-1961 (Box 57)
      - Schroeder, Werner, 1959-1967 (Box 57)
      - Selected Recent Acquisitions, 1960-1965 (Box 57)
      - Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs, 1961-1966 (Box 57)
      - Space Law Project, 1960-1962 (Box 57)
      - Specific Admissions Policies, 1964-1966 (Box 57)
      - Stason, E. Blythe, Portrait, 1960 (Box 57)
      - Statistics, Faculty, 1958-1959 (Box 57)
      - Statistics, Students, 1912-1914; 1941-1946; 2 folders (Box 57)
      - Statement of Policy 1968, 1971 Revision (Box 57)
      - Student Data File, 1965-1967 (Box 57)
      - Student Organizations, 1958-1963 (Box 57)
      - Summer School for Lawyers, 1960-1962 (Box 57)
      - United States Steel Foundation, 1967-1968 (Box 57)
      - University of Michigan, 1960-1965
        - Accounting Office (Box 57)
        - Calendar (Box 57)
        - Cumiskey, Ed (Box 57)
        - Development Council (Box 57)
        - Gift Receiving Office (Box 57)
        - Hatcher, Harlan (Box 57)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 57)
        - Niehuss, Marvin L (Box 57)
        - Walter, Erich (Box 57)
      - University Systems Committee, 1966; 2 folders (Box 57)
      - Veterans and Veterans Service, 1946-1951 (Box 57)
      - Visitors, 1966-1971; 4 folders (Box 57)
      - World War I, 1917-1919
        - Military Records of Law Students, 2 folders (Box 58)
        - Miscellaneous, 1917-1918 (Box 58)
        - Students Army Training Corps, 4 folders (Box 58)
        - Postwar, 1923-1936
          - League of Nations, 1923 (Box 58)
          - Military Science and Tactics, 1933 (Box 58)
          - University Peace Meeting, 1936 (Box 58)
      - World War II, 1941-1945
        - Association of American Law Schools (Box 58)
        - Deaths of Law School Alumni (Box 58)
        - Deferments-Selective Service (Box 58)
        - Draft Registration (Box 58)
        - Lectures on Military Law and War Emergency (Box 58)
        - Manual Advisory Boards for Registrants (Box 58)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 58)
        - National Defense Matters (Box 58)
        - Pamphlets (Box 58)
        - Physical Education for Men
          - Conditioning Courses (Box 58)
          - Enrollments, 1942-1947; 2 folders (Box 58)
        - University War Board (Box 58)
        - Veterans; Requirement for Admission (Box 58)
        - War Ration Book One (Box 58)
        - Post-War Affairs, 1945-1947
          - Correspondence (Box 58)
          - Enrollment (Box 58)
          - Faculty Post War Problems (Box 58)
          - Post War Committee (Box 58)
          - Public Law 16 (Box 58)
          - Veterans Services (Box 58)
        - Judge Advocate General's (JAG) School, 1942-1945
          - Class Lists (Box 58)
          - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Yazawa, Makoto (Box 58)
      - Yntema, Hessel E (Box 58)
    - Regents Communications, Reports, and Petitions, 1852-1962